so I've seen a lot of stuff on the
internet lately about hip hinging and
different drills um you can practice um
for example some people say you know
they teach the RDL where you teach
people how to sit back and touch their
butt to the wall so you know an
RDL okay touching your butt to the wall
that teaches people how to sit back well
that's a good drill and then another
good drill to kind of teach people to
sit back is something I do like this I
show people so many squatters strong
like bodybuilding type guys who are used
to squatting you know like a
bodybuilding style squat like that they
don't know how to sit back and they're
so afraid to lean forward but when I
teach the box squat I teach them you
know especially a high box squat I teach
them how to sit back and I kind of show
them you know if you're really good you
can really sit back watch how far I can
sit back my shin angle is negative now
and then I can come up
so you
know if you really know how to box squat
well you keep that vertical Shin but I
don't lift it from here cuz the bar
would be on my back and my feet are
right here you want the bar centered
over the feet so you would have to lean
in and then come up so there's different
types of teaching box what some people
just tap some people actually Rock but
um anyway this this is just a good drill
to have people
practice just to get them used to
sitting back touching their butt far
back because most people really stink at
it at first and then after trying that
drill they kind of get it anyway hope
you like the video thanks for watching